THE RED FISHES
Just like the last four days, today
the stormy northwest wind has continued...
...lashing the coast, and it seems
it ain't gonna decrease its fury.
The sea's appearance is astonishing.
The harbor is still closed.
- Good night.
- What a night!
- Dreadful.
Sorry, I didn't see you.
- Is that noise the sea?
- Yes, Miss. It's been the same...
- ...for a week...
- Sounds like it might burst in here!
You've got free rooms, haven't you?
You can have the entire hotel.
Gijon is dead in the off-season.
- We want three rooms with bathrooms.
- Three?
What's Carlos doing out there?
He's staring at a shop window
beside the hotel.
Hugo, do you hear the sea?
It must be tremendous.
I would like to get
closer to see it.
Would you please go outside and
tell that dummy to come in?
Kids nowadays...
- Is that all your luggage, Sir?
- No, outside there's a big valise.
No, no, let him get it inside,
let him take the trouble.
Well, Carlos, I accept your gift but now
get inside, your father's getting angry.
What? No way, it's too
cold to go outside.
You'll see it tomorrow.
Come on, hurry up.
Sign here, Ivan.
Let my son fill out his own.
- Well, being a kid...
- A kid? He's nineteen,
...if you think he's a kid...
Can you rent our rooms together?
Yes, whatever you like.
The whole hotel is empty.
I'll give you the second floor
suite, it's the best one.
May I, please?
What are you waiting for?
For my son?
Not at all.
Let him use his legs.
This way.
Poor boy, Carlos must be
tired too.
It's at the end of the corridor.
- Do you like it?
- Yeah, very good.
I would like to take a shower.
Is there hot water?
Yes, Miss.
It was boiling a while ago.
That's your room.
This one is yours.
For you and your son.
- Can we have dinner?
- Sure, but it must be cold meats,
...look what time it is.
- Cold meat for three,
...and three bottles of beer.
- I'll tell the waitress.
Hey! And three cups of coffee.
Ask the lady if she prefers
a cup of tea.
Miss?
Miss...
Wow, she's boiling!
How nice.
What a lovely kid!
You could have got your
suitcase upstairs, pretty boy.
Damn it! Why haven't you stuck it
in a place I know?
Carlos Pascal, nineteen.
I'll put you in jail
the same number of years!
- How frightening! The sound of the sea!
- Good night, miss.
- It's been the same all week.
- It must be tremendous.
- Which is the best place to see it?
- Santa Catalina...
...a promontory near by.
But they shouldn't go there,
it's terribly windy.
The view must be astonishing.
Why don't we get closer?
- Will he want to come?
- Sure, he will want to.
Hey, Carlos, would you like to...?
Stop that music.
I warn you it is very dangerous,
I won't go there even if...
- Besides, it's very dark.
- Well, it's only once in a lifetime.
As you like. You're gonna
get wet anyway.
- I'll wear my raincoat.
- O.K.
And the umbrella, if the wind
doesn't blow it away.
I will take both.
Hugo, tell him to hurry up.
Carlos, hurry up,
the dinner is ready.
At your service, colonel.
O.K., let's go.
Good night and enjoy your meal.
Help!
Hurry up!
They're in the dumping site.
Over there, in the dumping site.
Come on, cool it.
What happened?
Did he slip?
What were you doing here
at this hour of the night?
- We went there to see the sea.
- Do you live in Gijón?
We must look for him, I've gotta
look for him!
Let me go! Come with me,
he could be alive.
Let me go!
- Sit down!
O.K., what happened to your son?
He was walking in front of us,
when we reached the dumping site...
...he started running.
He entered the dumping site running.
I got scared. The wind was shaking us.
I shouted at him, but Carlos...
...was always nuts.
Always crazy...
Always laughing. Suddenly, I saw
him jump, sit on the guardrail...
...I run towards him, but...
...I didn't get there in time.
I saw him fall head over heels.
He was falling in circles and shouting.
Those were horrible screams.
- Where is he?
- What?
- Where is the father?
- Down there, with the other men.
- Have you talked to his wife?
- Not yet, do you want me to interrogate her?
Yeah, interrogate her.
Please, miss, make an effort,
drink it.
- Coffee will cheer you up.
- I don't want anything.
Leave her alone.
It'll be just a moment.
I have to ask you a few questions.
You must understand it.
Yes.
What's the profession of your husband?
What's his work?
He's not my husband, he's my fiancé.
We're gonna get married.
- Well. What's his profession?
- He's a writer. Novelist.
Do you think they've found anything?
I should be there.
I should be by his side...
Please, take it easy.
What's your profession?
I've heard you're an actress.
Yes, sir.
What did you come for? I mean,
what was the reason for this trip?
There was no special motive,
he had finished his novel and I...
...I asked for some days off
and we convinced Carlos...
...to come with us. We wanted
to travel all over the North.
- Your fiancé is a widower, isn't he?
- No, sir, he's single.
And the son?
Carlos was a natural son, he
has his father's surname.
I'm freezing.
Well, it's all over now.
That stupid cop was really
annoying me.
I wouldn't do this again, not
for all the gold in the world.
- Why don't you change clothes?
- I must have fever.
What a strange sensation
it is to lose a son.
Don't talk nonsense.
Why don't you take a hot shower?
I feel I have blood on my hands.
Don't dramatize, nobody
is watching you.
I really mean it!
The matter is finished.
Well...
...what do you say about
my performance?
Do you think I deserve to be
in suburban theater?
I would like to have seen
some others in my place.
You say that because you don't
know what having a son is like.
- You don't know how you can love him.
- You can keep on loving him...
- ...who prevents you from that?
- 19 years living with him...
...feeling him by my side
day after day.
Will you shut up?
Say no more nonsense.
You're nervous.
Come on, smoke a cigarette.
Why don't you start packing?
We have bloodstained hands
whether you want to or not.
Only fifteen days ago, I didn't
realize I had a son.
And now he's dead.
Things started getting
tangled up that night.
Ivón worked in that theatre,
she had a small role in...
...that silly revue, but she
was happy. Well...
...not that night. A letter drove
her up the wall. Just a letter.
Or maybe it was the letterhead.
On stage, Miss Ivón!
Come on, Ivón, get to work.
How boring are those dummies...
...in row 0.
Hey, Magda, do I have an idiot face?
Come on, tell me, do I?
Well, don't worry, we'll find
work in another place.
I don't care about that.
I don't mind if the...
...company goes into liquidation
or not.
All I wanna know is if I have
an idiot face.
Yes or no.
- What's the matter with you?
If Hugo comes, tell him to wait
for me. I gotta talk with him.
- What has he done to you?
- What am I gonna do to him? You should say.
Hi, Manolo.
Miss Ivón has been asking
for you all night long.
- Yeah? Is she there?
- She has just left.
Do you know it, Mr. Pascal?
This is over.
- What happened? No audience?
- What? It's all sold out.
There's been a row, do you understand?
There was a row between the...
...and the "White Horse".
The white horse?
Is there a horse in the play?
Shut up and perform. And take care
of your own horse or I'll eat it.
Hello, Ivón.
Hello, darling.
Do I have an idiot face?
Come on, tell me, do I?
Don't you laugh at me. Get out of here!
I don't wanna see you no more!
But, why?
What's up?
I know everything, do you hear me?
Everything!
So you're a writer, aren't you?
That's how you make a living, isn't it?
You're not a writer and
you have never been.
Well, that's what the
publishers also say.
- But, what is it all about?
- How ingenious you are!
You know what I'm talking about.
You're not a writer...
...and you're not waiting to
be published to marry me.
It's not true that you ain't
got no money.
You've had a bad dinner,
haven't you?
Liar! Are you gonna deny
you are a millonaire?
Yeah, millionaire. You're a millionaire
and you've been laughing at me.
Come on, Ivón, don't be silly,
I swear upon my name Hugo...
- Hugo is not your name!
- What are you saying?
Your name is Carlos,
Carlos Pascal.
How do you know it?
I didn't know you were
dealing with banks.
3,226,000 pesetas.
- Where did you get that?
- 3,226,000 pesetas.
It says so here. And you've been telling
me for a year when you get published...
Where did you get it?
Caretaker gave it to you, didn't he?
Yes.
I've told you a thousand times
not to go to my house.
I had to. I was desperate.
You know the company goes into liquidation
on Saturday and I ain't got no place...
...to rest my bones.
You don't care about that.
- I wish I were a millionaire.
- You are, you cynic.
- I make a living writing.
- How dare you?
- And my name is Hugo.
- Your name is Carlos.
Carlos is my son.
Are you married?
No.
It was...
...an affair, do you understand?
We had a child.
She didn't want to take care
of the baby and I hadn't...
...the courage to abandon him.
Who is she?
Are you gonna be jealous?
It was 19 years ago.
- 19 years...
And I haven't seen her again.
I wouldn't recognize her now.
Do you realize now why I hadn't
told you about it?
My son is almost your age.
I should've told you from the
beginning, but I hadn't the courage.
Well, this is over, isn't it?
Not for me. All I care about
is being your wife.
Really?
You're an angel and I love you
more than anything.
You hit hard, but you're
an angel.
We'll get married soon.
Why does your son have
those millions?
Aunt Angela gave them to him.
When she knew I was having a baby...
...she put that money in the bank,
and I was disinherited.
- Why?
- For having that baby.
She threw me out of his house.
She always had a very bad opinion of me.
She doesn't think
I'm a writer either.
- We agree on that.
- Shut up.
Hey, does your son know
I'm your fiancé?
I think so. We never talk
about that. Why?
Well, he's a millionaire. Maybe
he won't like that I work here.
What nonsense!
- Do you wanna meet him?
- You think I should?
Why not? I'm sure he'll
be very pleased.
Don't think he's silly.
He thinks about women like I do.
And what do you think
about them?
Living in a place like this
having 3,226,000 pesetas.
When did aunt Angela die?
She's living in the field,
in a magnificent castle.
Do you know what I'll do with that
money?
I'll live in "La Castellana".
He's gonna live there.
He wants to buy a flat.
Oh my God, what luck!
A very big one?
He says he wants so many rooms
to get lost in.
- What nonsense.
- Nonsense?
I like this house. It seems
genuine to me...
...from a romantic Madrid. All this
environment has its charm.
Its charm...
Carlos!
Are you there?
Well, it seems he's not here.
Carlos!
He must have gone for something.
He has left the light on.
Maybe he'll come back in a while.
You see? This is his room.
He's always here studying.
- Studying?
- He's finishing his third year of...
...Look, he's left a note.
"Dad, I've gone to study
at Fernando's place."
"I'll be back late. Don't wait up
for me. See you tomorrow, colonel."
Colonel?
He's called me that ever since
he saw a movie about India.
- What career is he studying for?
- Architecture.
Well, should we go or do you
want a cup of coffee?
He's a millionaire and he
studies. That's terrific.
All of him is terrific: likeable,
a good boy and very clever.
Don't you have any pictures
of him? Is he so ugly?
Ugly? You're crazy.
Do you know how tall he is?
1.85 meters, a Tarzan,
and his face...
Good heavens, what a boy!
- Let's take it in the sitting room.
- Yeah, as you like.
I don't like to be in here.
I don't wanna see his personal things.
I like him to be free.
Close the door.
Turn on the light.
I'm very happy today, Ivón.
I've been with a publisher this evening.
I gave him my novel. He'll answer
me tomorrow, let's see if...
...this time I'm luckier.
Here.
What do you think of my flat?
It isn't as ugly as Carlos says.
When he gets married and goes
to his flat in La Castellana...
- ...you and I will move here.
- Does he have a girlfriend?
I guess so.
I'm gonna bring more coffee.
I never meddle with his things.
A bitch.
She'll be a girl just like
all the others.
Think of it, a handsome millionaire.
That's why's she got to be a bitch?
She must have something special.
Carlos ain't no fool.
- He's deeply in love.
- Have you met her?
No.
- Then, how do you know it?
- Well, I deduce it.
Should I fill it up?
One day I caught him in his
room kissing a picture and...
...what a kiss!
Do you know who was arriving
when I was leaving?
"The White Horse" in a big car.
I bet he makes peace with the Tall
One
and the company doesn't go into...
...liquidation on Saturday.
What's the matter with you?
Did you have another dispute?
Hey, what would you think if you
saw a man kissing a picture of you?
- That he's crazy about me.
- And what would you do?
I would faint.
And if he is also young,
handsome and an architect?
Stop, please. How do you know
it was a picture of you?
And he's also thinking of marrying.
Please, Ivón, I suffer
from heart problems.
- Which picture was it?
- Well, just for example...
- ...say it was a picture of me.
- What an example!
- He's crazy about me.
- Well, give him a couple of coins.
- He doesn't need them, he has a lot.
- Oh, yeah?
- Three million pesetas.
- Well, alright.
- How much did you say?
- Three million pesetas.
Do you know I heard three
million pesetas?
I said three million pesetas.
You see? I heard three million
pesetas again.
Three, pal, three!
Yeah, yeah, I understand three,
but after that I hear million.
Millions, idiot, millions.
Yeah, yeah, idiot. With three
million anyone is an idiot.
He's gonna buy a huge flat in
La Castellana, with running water.
- Can you imagine that?
- No.
All for himself?
- For himself or for him and me.
- But, has he met Hugo?
- Yes.
Well, so what?, I don't think
you're gonna vacillate.
I don't think you're so silly.
Silly idiot.
Is it possible?
There's one thing I haven't
explained to you yet.
The boy is...
Look, I'll tell you tomorrow,
today I'm very tired.
Don't you know if he has
a brother?
Listen...
...what would happen if one day
I came to the theatre...
...with my own car and with a
marvellous fur coat...
...draped over my shoulders?
I have always dreamt of that,
to have my own fur coat...
...and let it lie upon
my shoulders.
- Is Mr. Muro here?
- Yes, in his office.
Come in.
Good morning.
How are you?
Well, I've just read it. Something
very curious happened to me.
It interested me a lot.
It's amazing, one of the best...
...I have ever read. But in the
last 30 pages, I was...
...surprised. They're absurd,
that ending is complete nonsense.
Illogical. What the hell happened?
I'm not the one who decides
the ending but the characters.
Right, characters command.
But characters are fictional.
You haven't created men and women
but puppets, that's why...
- ...the story is unbelievable.
- I think they're human.
They live decently for some time
and then get tired of that.
All of us get tired of living
decently. Some admit it...
...and others think it. There's a
rebel inside of us, and my characters...
...revolt, because they're
human. Puppets never revolt.
As a publisher I'm interested in real
stories, that's what makes money...
...people don't want fantasies.
It's
like in cinema, "neorealismo"...
- ...the real life.
- Real life?
You mean to show the rotten
insides of men and cities?
In those films I have only seen
dirty streets, clothes hanging out...
- ...and children full of snot.
- That's it, that's it, it's human.
That it's human is fantasy!
Scratching, eating, sleeping...
...and moving among dung
is also done by animals...
...cows, for example.
Will you please stop
admiring yourself?
Hey, do you think I'm fine
in this pic?
- Amazing, sensational.
- Do you think he'll like it?
Are you gonna send it to him?
Sure, Ivón, send it to him.
And with a dedication in it.
An insinuating one.
An indirect one.
For example...
- "I'm crazy about you."
- How can I say that?
It must be something refined.
For example...
- "To Carlos with affection."
- "With a lot of affection."
Listen, do you know what I'd do?
I'd reserve a box for him tonight.
For this evening, Hugo
is coming tonight.
You're right. I'll ask the
management. Besides, write...
...a note, tell him to come
for you at the end of the show.
Rehearsal, miss, master is here.
I'm coming...
I've always dreamt of mink,
of having a mink coat...
- ...and wearing it on my shoulders.
- What's the matter with you, miss?
Just a moment, just a moment,
I'll be right back.
Here's the box reservation.
Still writing?
- What is it, the note?
- Yeah.
I won't be disturbed if you pay
me a visit in my dressing room.
Get out and wait for me
in the bar.
- Like that, Ivón?
- You can't be here.
I'll get the clothes to get
dressed in any other place.
Who do you think I am?
- Good luck.
- Thanks.
Come in.
What's up? I've been this morning
to the publisher.
- Why are you coming at these hours?
- Which ones?
These ones.
At the evening show.
It's been spoilt. I was nearby.
Besides, I wanna tell you something.
I was thinking, I wanna go to Barcelona
and try the local publishers.
What's the matter with you?
Aren't you glad I came?
Sure, sure.
- What do you think?
- Very good.
I'm leaving tonight.
Listen, Hugo, why don't you wait
for me in the bar while I get dressed?
Don't you have a screen?
Do you know my novel's flaw...
...according to the publisher?
It's not human, it's not realistic.
Always the same.
- Why don't you get out?
- I've got too much imagination, Ivón.
- Don't open the door!
- There's no rehearsal tomorrow, Miss Ivón.
Oh, fine.
- What were you saying about imagination?
- Just that.
Imagination is a flaw for
writers nowadays.
Please, wait for me
in the bar, Hugo.
- You don't care about my problems, do you?
- Yes, but I don't understand them.
Solve them for yourself. Don't
you have a lot of imagination?
You too? You're getting
tired of me.
Don't you see I'm working for us,
so we can get married...
...and you can leave this pigsty?
- Leave me alone! You're hurting me.
- Miss Ivón's dressing room?
- This door.
I'm going to Barcelona. Talking
with you is useless.
Don't go now, wait.
Don't you hear it?
Miss Ivón?
What are you saying?
- Miss Ivón?
- Yes, that's me.
Here, from "Flores La Camelia."
What a bouquet!
Tremendous!
Thanks, thank you very much.
- Who sent it?
- Sorry, I almost forgot.
Give it to me!
Let's see who's your admirer.
- Give it to me!
- Let me open it.
Give me that right now.
It's mine.
What the hell is wrong
with you this evening?
Why don't you want me to read it?
Do you think I care about...
...dummies who spend their
money buying flowers?
I forgot to tell you: I
sent those flowers.
I was down due to the publisher's
denial and I thought it'd help you...
...to bear the bad news.
The note says: "I always
love you, Hugo."
I won't be disturbed if you pay me
a visit in my dressing room. Ivón.
Why has Hugo come?
The other one must have
seen him and got away.
You must phone him.
You know his telephone number,
don't you?
Apologize to him, tell him
Hugo is a relative of yours.
Hugo is his father.
- His father?
- Yeah, his father.
Good night, Mr. Pascal. A man
came asking for you.
He came three times. He said
it was very urgent.
- Did he tell you who he was?
- He left his card.
He said you should go see him,
or telephone him.
- Allright, thanks, Gregorio.
- You're welcome, Mr. Pascal.
SALVADOR CASTRO
LAWYER
- Hello?
- Is that you, Carlos?
No, no. I'm not her, I'm a friend,
her close friend. She's here...
...by my side. She'll take the phone.
She's signaling to give her...
...the phone.
She'll take it right away.
- I don't want to. Hang up.
- Come on, he's waiting.
Tell him you can meet someplace.
- I said I don't want to!
- Are you dumb, girl?
She'll be here right away, she's coming.
Goodbye, Carlos, pleased to meet you.
That's enough.
Excuse me, please,
I understand you.
I was also surprised to see
your father at that hour.
Excuse me, please,
I understand you.
I was also surprised to see
your father at that hour.
He came to tell me he's going to
Barcelona tonight.
And that's why I dared
to phone you.
And that's why I dared to phone you.
I know he's in the station.
You were expecting me to phone you,
weren't you?
Please, Carlos, don't misunderstand me.
I can't betray your father...
...but I can't betray
myself either.
That's the same way
you feel, isn't it?
One doesn't know what love is
until it suddenly arises.
Listen, let's talk.
I'll be waiting for you tonight
at the end of the show.
- What did he say?
- Not even a word.
He must be shaking like jelly.
One doesn't know what love is
until it suddenly arises.
Don't you hear it?
Open the door.
Wait.
I'm sorry, I don't wanna bother you
but I gotta finish my report.
It'll just be a moment.
- What was your son wearing?
- Well, he was wearing a raincoat.
And a grey suit underneath.
I'm not quite sure.
Are you sure it was an accident?
I mean, was there anything
wrong with the boy?
Any intimate annoyance that could
have led him to take that decision.
Suicide?
Good Heavens, don't speak nonsense.
Carlos was a normal kid.
Sometimes there are problems
parents don't know.
I beg you not to get things
out of proportion.
Well, that's all.
If there's anything new
we'll let you know.
Thank you.
Oh, you'll have to stay here
for a few days.
- What?
- Maybe a week.
Think about it, there are some
formalities that must be done.
Think about it? What the hell should I
think about and what have I to do...
...with your profession? Besides all
my pain, I have to stay here.
Can't you see I can't bear it
any longer?
I understand you, but...
If you have to do any formality
just go ahead and do it.
But leave me alone. We're going
to Madrid right now.
You can't do that.
I tell you once more you can't
leave for a few days.
Why did you get angry?
Why do you wanna leave?
We're very confortable here.
- Mr. Commissioner!
- What's the matter?
- An urgent call from Madrid.
- From headquarters?
I don't know, they only said
it was very urgent.
Well, let's go.
They've called three times,
Mr. Jesus, they seem very angry.
- Isn't it from headquarters?
- No, sir, it's a lawyer from Madrid.
Hello? Yeah, Commissioner
speaking.
Talk to me.
Will you please tell me in which
hotel Mr. Hugo Pascal is lodged?
And please, what has happened?
Any news about that terrible accident?
- The paper is very clear.
- There's nothing more to know.
We're trying to find the body
but it's very difficult.
Excuse me, will you please tell me
with whom I'm talking to?
Write down Mr. Salvador
Castro, lawyer.
Are you a relative?
I'm the executor of Mr. Pascal's
late aunt's estate.
I'm shocked, she died 5 days ago
and now the boy.
It's terrible, he was about
to inherit.
Well, will you please tell me
in which hotel he's lodged?
At the Savoy, 2201.
Does Mr. Pascal have more sons?
Good.
You're welcome, Sir.
Poor boy, he was the only son.
And very bad luck, he dies...
...when he was about to inherit.
I have always said money
brings bad luck.
Mr. Jesus, don't you think we should
listen to that telephone call?
- Why?
- I don't know, don't listen to me...
...but when money is in the middle...
The son was about to inherit
and dies in strange circumstances...
...and now the money goes
straight to his father.
In strange circumstances?
Going to see the sea and slips isn't...
Don't you think it's strange?
Going to see the sea at night
with that horrible storm.
It isn't logical.
What are you thinking of?
Instead of slipping it could
have been...
- What are you basing that on?
- On nothing.
It could have been done better
than that if they'd wanted to.
- I know it makes no sense.
- To get the son's inheritance?
Do you think everybody that
inherits is an assassin?
Hey, my aunt Jacinta is ill and she's
gonna give me an amount of money.
If I were you I'd listen
to that telephone call.
Hello.
Just a moment.
A phone call from Madrid.
Who's speaking?
Oh, tell me, tell me.
I'm sorry about the events, Mr. Pascal.
I don't wanna ask you about...
... the reasons for this
journey, you can do...
...whatever you want, but why did
you take your son with you?
Don't you know I must open your aunt's
will the day after tomorrow...
...and your son needs to be there?
You're wrong if you think I'm
gonna listen to this nonsense.
I came here because I wanted to, and I
took my son with me for the same reason.
Do you want anything else?
Just to remind you that the day after
tomorrow I must open the will...
...and now you are the only heir,
as you should know.
If your aunt were still alive
I don't think she would like to see...
...you win in the end.
ACCIDENT OR SUICIDE?
Son of writer Hugo Pascal falls to
the sea from Cimadevilla cliffs.
The corpse hasn't been found.
You're right, it's a rented one.
- Good night, gentlemen.
- Come on, don't be a joker.
- Are they still up?
- People from Madrid stay up late.
They're in the first-floor hall.
When they came last night, it was
about this hour, wasn't it?
Exactly the same. My shift
starts at a quarter to one.
Listen, I've read in the paper
that you said...
...he asked you to accompany them
to the promontory...
...to show them the way.
Yes, Sir. They told me:
"Come on, come with us"
- Are you sure that's what they told you?
- Well...
You see, I've tried to make it
more thrilling.
- Did they tell you that or not?
- No. But they could have told me that.
I...
That was impossible, boss,
they didn't want any witnesses.
In the paper you say that the boy seemed
to have a premonition of his death...
...and that he shook hands with you
with tears in his eyes.
I said that to make it more thrilling.
Just to make it more thrilling.
- Are you dumb?
- Not at all, Mr. Commissioner.
I'm just an entertaining man.
I have always hated dull stories.
The sudden entrance of the boy
must also be for thrills.
- The sticking of the pen and...
- No, no, Sir.
You can see the pierced paper.
Do you see the mark?
Then I got angry...
...as I used to get angry when
customers would stick the pen...
- ...in the counter.
- Do they stick the pen in the counter?
- And I told the boy: "Hey, boy..."
- But you didn't see him.
You said that when you got down
he was inside the elevator.
You're right.
If you continue being
entertaining, I'm gonna...
Alright. He got inside the elevator
and went up to his flat.
- Which floor?
- Which one could it be?
The floor, of course, the second.
Who told him to go up
to the second floor?
If you didn't tell him and
neither did the waitress...
...how did he know the
number of the floor?
I swear nobody told him that.
So he guessed the floor.
And the number of the room...
...'cos there are more than one.
- Fifteen.
Yeah, it's strange.
Maybe he heard it.
With the door closed?
Please, say something.
I was telling him I'm not sure
of having...
Is this door as it was yesterday?
The same way.
Was it without the doorhandle?
I take it off every night
when I start my shift, so...
...I can sleep peacefully. If anybody
wants to come in he must ring the bell.
Then, where did the boy come in from?
If this man was upstairs,
who opened the door?
If nobody opened the door, did he
filter through the glass?
Maybe it was opened.
Hello?
Yes, sir, it's ready.
I'll take it right away.
It's them.
The coffee for Mr. Pascal!
I admit there's something
strange here.
Maybe we should go and ask them
about it, they may have...
...an explanation.
- Everything was phony.
They brought him here dead. They made
everybody believe he was alive...
...so the accident could be
justified.
What they threw from the promontory
was a corpse.
- They must've killed him in Madrid.
- Where did they bring him?
- How did they get him in here?
- Think of that big suitcase.
The caretaker says it was
very heavy...
Half past one, how awful!
In Madrid everything starts
at these hours.
The curtain must be falling now.
Don't worry, I'll serve it.
And you, arriving in the
dressing room to pick me up.
I'm willing to come back to Madrid.
One doesn't know what love is
until it suddenly arises.
I'd like to talk with you. I'll be
waiting for you at the end of the show.
I'll be waiting for you tonight
at the end of the show.
Mr. Pascal is late, isn't he?
No, he's not in Madrid, he has
left for Barcelona.
Are you staying?
- Goodbye, Mr. Manolo.
- Good night, Miss.
- What are you doing here?
- Just looking at you.
- Hadn't you left for Barcelona?
- Where did you come from?
From the theatre.
They've been reading a play.
Maybe we won't go into liquidation.
Why did you tell me you were
going to Barcelona?
I'm leaving tomorrow.
There were no tickets left.
Then, why didn't you come to
the theatre as usual?
Carlos suddenly got ill.
Give me a cigarette.
Suddenly? How strange.
- Will you please look in your handbag?
- Yeah, yeah.
There must be one or two left.
So you've been at home.
Poor man, and I was thinking
bad things.
- Bad things about whom?
- About you, silly.
I thought you'd left for Barcelona
without waving me goodbye.
You know this evening you
didn't wave me goodbye.
Hey, I love you spite of all,
do you hear? I love you.
Don't force me to do something
I don't want to.
- But if you insist, I will.
- What's the matter with you?
I want us to get married right away.
With the money you earn...
...and the pension the
bank pays me...
- Pension? The bank?
- Where do you think I get money from?
From the interest payments
on my son's capital.
You cash them.
I feed him and pay for his
career.
That's how I make a living.
That's another way aunt Angela
found to embarrass me.
It's a small amount, you know?
But the three of us could live.
What do you think?
15 days more and we'll get married.
- I'll have to keep on working, won't I?
- Well, just for the moment.
- What does for the moment mean?
- Until my first novel is published.
- Come on, leave me alone.
- You don't believe in me, do you?
You don't care about me because
I can't give you any money.
That's the only thing you care about,
millions. You don't care if I'm dumb.
'Cos everyone who has millions
is a dumb one.
You're lying and you know it.
- Carlos is...
- Carlos is a dummy.
What's the matter with you?
You're jealous.
You should be ashamed,
talking like that...
...when you're living
at his expense.
- Good morning, may I come in?
- Ah, hello. Come in.
- You get up early, don't you?
- It is only work.
I'm not used to going to
my clients' houses...
...but it seems it's the only
way to find you at home.
Didn't the caretaker tell you
I came three times?
- Yes, he gave me your card.
- Why didn't you phone me?
Look, Mr. Castro, I'm not your
client.
That's my aunt.
I only care about people I like,
and you and my aunt...
...are none of those.
Will you tell me what do you want?
Your aunt is dying. She wants
to talk with your son.
She is dying? I didn't even
know she was ill.
It's not that. She is very old.
- May I talk with Mr. Carlos?
- Come in. Please, come in.
- Poor aunt Angela.
- She wants to see him.
- Does she wanna see me?
- She wants no part of you.
She wants to see your son.
Is he
at home? I've gotta talk with him.
No, he's not at home.
I heard him leaving very early.
Are you sure she doesn't want
to see me?
- It's impossible.
- Why?
I don't understand why she
doesn't remember me.
She remembers everything,
she's got a good memory.
- Have you talked with her?
- Yeah.
- Did you talk about me?
- God forbid!
She wants to say goodbye
to your son, so please...
...tell him that. He must leave now
or he won't arrive on time.
Carlos!
You?
Carlos couldn't come.
He has a lot of work to do.
How are you, aunt Angela?
- You're lying.
You haven't wanted him to come.
You have never let him come.
And I know why.
Get out! Go away.
No, I want you to forgive me.
It all happened a long time ago.
- Go away, send me your son.
- Listen to me.
Get out, Hugo.
Please, you can't remember that.
It was 19 years ago,
don't you understand?
I would be lying if I said I
forgive you. You hurted me so much...
Do you remember the day
I said it to you?
You had just told me you wouldn't
give me any more money.
I was desperate.
I wasn't born to work,
the way you wanted me to.
I was born...
...for writing.
For making up stories.
For releasing all the
fantasy I had inside.
You never had
fantasy, but vanity.
It's true. I've got vanity
and I've got fantasy.
No, if you had fantasy you wouldn't
have a baby in that mean way...
...so miserable.
My son doesn't exist, aunt Angela.
He has never existed.
He's a son of my
fantasy,
of my vanity.
I wanted to prove to you
that I had imagination.
I had to create him to live,
to keep on fighting.
I was sure you won't refuse
to give him money to live.
And I will live with that money.
When I came back to Madrid I went
to the court and lied to them.
They never check. That was
the document I sent to you.
At the beginning it was just a game,
it was to create a character...
...and make him live on the paper.
To give him a personality...
...and change it as he was growing up.
With his infatuations and caprices.
It was also funny to make him up
in the physical sense.
I gave him the color of your eyes,
aunt, I have always liked it.
That's a lie. You're denying him
to be forgiven.
- I've lived 19 years with him.
- You're lying.
He's been my pride. No writer ever
created a character more human.
I have lived with him, I've seen him
and I've touched him.
And I've loved him like a son.
And he has loved me.
Sorry, aunt, I think I'm
gonna go crazy.
What about the letters and the presents?
And those postcards he sent me...
...from Rome, with
such dedications...?
It isn't possible.
You're lying.
One New Year's Eve he sent me a
present and you didn't know it.
It was bought in Rome by the same
friend who sent you the postcards.
What about that illness he suffered?
You asked me for money for medicine.
I needed money to go to Barcelona.
I also needed money when...
...I asked you for toys and books,
and for the school fee.
I've never asked you for any
more money than I needed.
- God will punish you, Hugo.
- He's already punishing me.
My son is turning against me.
The woman I'm gonna marry
wants to cheat on me with him.
I have no money and he's rich.
Are you nuts? Tell her
he doesn't exist.
What will be the use of
telling her the truth?
What will be the use of telling her
she has fallen in love with a shadow?
No. She must return to me just for me.
Not because the other doesn't exist.
I must convince her I'm better
than him, much better.
I am a writer.
I must triumph.
I swear I'll triumph.
I'll fight against my son.
I will defeat him.
- I must defeat him.
- Hugo, come here, don't go.
Phone him again. He'll answer
sooner or later.
He won't. I'm sure he doesn't
answer because...
...he knows it's me. He must be
waiting for me to go to his house...
...begging on my knees.
- That way everything will be fixed.
- Begging on my knees?
That's what you think.
- You should go to his house.
- Thank you very much.
Hey, give me back the sandwich.
It was a salami one.
Right away.
You can do what you want, but
I would do my best now that...
...Hugo is journeying.
Do you
know what happens to that boy?
He doesn't dare to come close
while his father is around.
Listen, leave his father alone.
Have a quarrel with him, that way
everything will be fixed.
It must be hard to take
your father's fiancé away.
- I can't quit Hugo.
- Are you gonna marry both?
No, of course not.
But I love Hugo.
I swear I love him.
I don't know how to quit him.
You're doing fine, you've got
to follow...
...your heart's impulses.
- Will you give me his telephone number?
- What for?
- To go out with him tonight.
- You've got a nerve, Magda.
- There are no noble impulses for you.
- Sure...
...my heart is asking me
for noble millions.
Listen, why don't you
make Hugo leave you?
That's different, isn't it?
Your conscience would be clear.
- Hugo won't leave me.
- Make him jealous, with his son.
Here, wear this bracelet.
Miss Ivón.
- Miss Ivón, phone call.
- Who is it?
Mr. Pascal.
Ivón?
Hello.
I have just arrived.
Yes, she died.
Thanks.
What? Rehearsing?
You didn't go into liquidation.
No, the "White Horse" has been
bridled again.
Besides, there's another number,
a magician.
Hey, do you know who I thought
it was?
Carlitos.
Carlos, your son.
The other day I phoned to know
when you were coming back.
He's very nice, isn't he?
Very, very nice.
- He's always been a womanizer.
- Yeah, he seems very dangerous.
I'll have to be careful.
Well, you'll come later, won't you?
Then, goodbye.
Great, and this evening you'll tell
him this is your mother's bracelet.
- My mother's bracelet?
- Yeah, he won't believe you.
Read them again, please. Maybe
you'll like one of them.
Don't insist on it. I don't deal
with fantastical novels.
They're not fantastical.
You've got too much imagination
and your characters are phantoms.
You can't cheat the readers by making
them believe that your characters...
...can exist. The day you create
a character and you make him...
...so human that the readers believe it,
that day my doors will be opened...
...to you again.
Hello, Manolo.
Have you seen we're not going
into liquidation?
The "White Horse" has just
passed by.
Has a horse passed by?
- And with money.
- Wow!
Hugo, congratulations, I didn't
know you had such a...
...nice son. I was shocked,
he's terrific.
So...
- ...my son was here.
- Yes, in the dressing room.
On your guard, Miss Ivón!
Is that you?
Hello, Hugo, just a moment.
- With whom have you been taking coffee?
- With no one. I took it all alone.
- Two?
- Yeah, I was cold.
- Now you smoke black tobacco.
- It must be the best boy's...
- ...who brought us the coffees.
- Us?
The, the coffees.
What's the matter with you?
- What a nice new bracelet.
- New? I've had it for years...
...it was from my mother.
So, my son has been here,
hasn't he?
- No.
- No?
Oh yes, and you introduced him
to Magda.
I...? I tell you, no.
Who has told you that nonsense?
Magda.
- Did you take coffe here?
- It's a lie, I swear it.
That girl is dumb!
Believe me, Hugo, why should
I deny it?
She told you we were here all alone,
and that we locked the door, eh?
- I think she's capable.
- It doesn't matter.
She didn't tell me so much.
It's you who's saying that.
I hate insinuations.
- What has happened? Tell me.
- He fell into the trap.
My mother's daughter
is very clever.
Look out! He's coming.
- I'm going to Barcelona tonight.
- For how long?
Four or five days.
Carlos, where are you, boy?
Pretty boy, pleasant boy.
May I come in?
I've got to tell you
something, young boy.
Aren't you studying?
Sleeping instead of being
with your girlfriend?
Your visit to the dressing room
has made you feel bad.
To see her in those shorts
You rascal, I know...
...you're drunk, drunk
on coffee, aren't you?
She has fallen in love
with you.
It's not you but your millions!
He's a good boy...
...but she doesn't care at all.
You're a little dirty...
...but you have millions.
Millions...
An architect, and I am
a poor rat.
A poor rat going crazy.
Miss Ivón, Miss Ivón...
...Miss Ivón, Miss Ivón...
Miss Ivón. From a man in a taxi.
Thanks.
- What's the matter?
- Nothing. Eat and shut up.
My beauty, Ivón: We're gonna meet
at last, my father is going...
...to Barcelona tonight and I'll
walk him to the station.
Wait for me in my flat.
Carlos.
Fantastic, there you are.
Go there right away.
I was sure he would answer.
I guess you won't forget
about me, will you?
Do you think I should go?
Ivón, don't you realize what
all of this meana?
What do you mean?
'Cos I know what this means.
I'm refering to 3,226,000 pesetas.
A big castle and a lot of
mink coats.
You're stupid.
Come, we've gotta talk.
Wait here, Mau-Mau.
- Well, OK.
- What did you call him?
- Mau-Mau, that's his wrestling name.
His name is Manolo,
but he thinks it's corny.
Listen, Ivón, do you see Mau-Mau?
Well, someone like him is waiting
for you the day Hugo quits you.
'Cos Hugo will quit you. He won't
marry you before he...
...triumphs as a novelist.
And he'll triumph as a novelist...
...the day I become fire chief.
- Hugo will marry me, Magda.
- If he marries you...
...you'll starve and your life
will be all boredom.
With Mau-Mau I'll learn
some chokeholds, but you?
What have you to do
with literature?
Listen, three million, no more
starving and no more orders...
...from the "Tall One"
and the impresario.
Coats, cars, and a flat
in La Castellana.
The life, Ivón, the life.
- I'll go.
- Sure.
Look, Magda, we're good friends
if we don't talk about that...
...and you know what I mean.
Do you see this key?
He's gonna swallow it.
I swear it.
I'll go there and make him
swallow it.
I've been thinking it would be
better not to go. That's what...
...an educated woman would do
when somebody got her wrong.
But I'm not educated nor
well-mannered. I am...
...a coarse one, Magda. And I
wanna make him swallow it.
Maybe Hugo doesn't have any money,
but he's never talked to me that way.
Can you see the difference, Magda?
No, not you. I know it.
You came to stay with him!
To stay with him!
How could I have been so blind?
How haven't I known before what you were?
Why have I loved you so much?
Why?
The damn money drove you crazy!
Get out of my house!
Get out!
Hugo, please listen to me.
I couldn't quit you even if I'd
get all the money in the world.
Get out of here.
It was the money, you're right.
You can spit on me...
I don't even know him.
But his money drove me crazy.
You can trample on me...
...but you're the one I like.
- Get out, Ivón, get out of here.
- I didn't come to stay with your son.
- You're lying!
I swear it.
- You came to stay with him.
- I swear not, ask Magda.
Phone her. She's at the theatre bar,
phone her, she'll tell you.
But you're right, Hugo, I thought
of leaving you because of his money.
I've been an idiot, but I've starved
so many times. I'm tired of fighting.
I know I have no excuse,
but this is the naked truth.
You don't know how a woman can feel
when a man with millions...
...pays attention to her.
When I found my pictures
in his drawer...
- I put them there.
- What?
And it was me who received
your note about that box seat.
And when you phoned him that night
and you talked with him...
...you talked with me.
I am my son, you dummy!
Carlos is just a fantasy.
He has never existed.
You've fallen in love
with the air, stupid.
I've been doing for 19 years what
you did this evening in the...
- ...dressing room with the bracelet.
- You're lying.
You're saying that to take
him out of my head.
Phone Magda, phone her.
I swear I loathe your son.
Shut up!
Do you think I need to cheat you?
- Carlos doesn't exist.
- But he was in the box that evening.
- It was a friend of mine.
- What about the bank?
That's true, don't worry...
...the 3,226,000 pesetas exist.
They're in the bank, just for...
...a few days. This evening the
lawyer phoned me to tell me...
...my aunt's will will be opened
in a week and my son...
...must be there.
Then this farce will be uncovered
and I'll go to jail.
You've gotta find a way out,
make up something, find an excuse...
...for your son not to be
there that day.
More lies?
Kill him!
Didn't you give birth to him?
Think of it, find a way out.
Aren't you a novelist?
- Good evening, sir.
- Good evening.
- What a night!
- Dreadful.
Sorry, I hadn't seen you.
- Is that sound the sea?
- Yes, Miss. It's been the same...
...for a week..
- Sounds like it might burst in here.
You've got free rooms, haven't you?
You can have the entire hotel.
In this season of the year Gijon is dead.
- We want three rooms with bathrooms.
- Three?
What's Carlos doing out there?
He's staring at a shop window
beside the hotel.
Hugo, do you hear the sea?
It must be tremendous.
I would like to get closer
to see it.
Would you please go outside and
tell that dummy to come in?
Kids nowadays...
- Is that all your luggage, Sir?
- No, outside there's a big valise.
No, no, let him get it inside,
let him take the trouble.
Well, Carlos, I accept your gift but now
get inside, your father's getting angry.
What? No way. It's too
cold to go outside.
You'll see it tomorrow.
Come on, hurry up.
- Do you like it?
- Yeah, very good.
I would like to take a shower.
Is there hot water?
Yes, Miss.
It was boiling a while ago.
That's your room.
This one is yours.
For you and your son.
- Can we have dinner?
- Sure, but it must be cold meat...
...look what time it is.
- Cold meat for three...
- ...and three bottles of beer.
- I'll tell the waitress.
Hey! And three cups of coffee.
Ask the lady if she prefers
a cup of tea.
Miss?
Miss...
Wow, she's boiling!
- It's done.
- OK.
Help me, take out the L.P.
- Do you think they'll recognize my voice?
- No, it always changes when it's recorded.
- When should I start talking?
- In this white spot.
Go, Ivón, and wet your hair,
don't forget it.
- How frightening! The sound of the sea!
- Good night, miss.
- It's been the same all week.
- It must be tremendous.
- Which is the best place to see it?
- Santa Catalina...
...a promontory near by.
But they shouldn't go there,
it's terribly windy.
The view must be astonishing.
Why don't we get closer?
- Will he want to come?
- Sure, he'll want to.
Hey, Carlos, would you like to...?
Stop that music.
I warn you, it is very dangerous.
I wouldn't go there even if...
- Besides, it's very dark.
- Well, it's only once in a lifetime.
As you like. You're gonna
get wet anyway.
- I'll wear my raincoat.
- O.K.
And the umbrella, if the wind
doesn't blow it away.
I will take both.
Hugo, tell him to hurry up.
Carlos, hurry up,
dinner is ready.
At your service, colonel.
Hugo, Hugo, what's up?
I've taken fright at you!
What were you thinking of?
You've been like that
for half an hour.
- I was thinking of his last words.
- Whose?
- At your service, colonel.
- Are you crazy? What's this all about?
Come on, take your coffee.
I'll go to bed because...
Good night.
Excuse me if I've turned
this on.
Good night.
I am the Commissioner.
Believe me if I tell you I deeply
regret this misfortune.
- Mind if I ask you some questions?
- At this hour?
The sooner the better,
so you'll be able...
- ...to go back to Madrid.
- What do you want to ask?
I'd like to know which way your
son used to enter the hotel.
You went upstairs with
the caretaker before him.
Nobody opened the door
for your son.
Can you tell me which way he used?
It seems to be a riddle.
What do I get if I solve it?
It could influence the judge
to place no obstacle before...
...your parole.
- Is that a threat?
- Where did your son come in?
- Through the door.
The door can't be opened from the
outside, Miss. It closes itself.
Well, somebody must've opened it.
Who knows?
Nobody did. And he went up to the second
floor and nobody had told him to.
Why?
Have you ever heard a more
stupid interrogation?
What the hell can we know?
What do you mean with all this?
- Your son didn't enter the hotel.
- But he did enter.
You're nuts!
Next time you insult me,
I'll arrest you.
- Hey, I warn you!
- Shut up, Hugo, shut up.
This man is right,
excuse him.
Then, who signed the register?
I can't answer something that
is based on the absurdity...
- ...that my son didn't enter here.
- Listen, I'm gonna tell you clearly...
...what I think.
Your son didn't enter...
Wait, I warn you that you're
insulting my...
...pain as a father with no
scruples.
You enter my room...
...by force and start a
nonsense interrogation.
You're going too far and I'll
notify the...
...General Bureau of Security.
- OK, go ahead.
But nobody saw your son
entering the hotel.
That's a lie!
The caretaker and the waitress
did see him.
Call the waitress and come
here, both of you.
Alright, Sir.
The Commissioner called for us.
- Good evening.
- The Commissioner?
- He's upstairs.
This man from Madrid
has asked for him.
I'll tell him.
The Commissioner?
There's a man from Madrid
asking for you.
Tell him to wait in the hall.
I'll be right there.
Come in, come in.
Did you see the son
of this man?
- No, I didn't see him.
- She's lying!
You didn't see him?
Didn't he have dinner with us?
- No sir, I didn't see him.
- Use your memory.
Don't you remember I entered here to
ask him if he wants to come with us...
- ...to the promontory?
- But I didn't see him, Sir.
I heard him saying he wanted to
go to the promontory, but...
- Did you hear him?
- Yes.
- Didn't you see him afterwards?
- No, Sir.
I swear it.
- Did you hear him? Is that true?
- Yes, Sir.
- Are you sure?
- The caretaker heard him too.
- Why didn't you say it sooner?
I forgive you, Commissioner...
...I understand you're
fulfiling your duty.
I know it sounds like
a novel, but...
Well, what are we waiting for?
I wanna go to sleep.
Stop that music!
Who are you to touch that?
I warn you I have less patience
than the Commissioner.
Take it easy. I too am
fulfilling my duty.
Music helps me to think.
Do you want me not to think?
Hello?
I want you to hear it too.
Hurry up, come down.
He has just told me something
very strange.
He has been investigating
in Madrid on his own.
- Did he do it personally?
- Personally, yes.
Come down. You were right,
but you can't imagine why.
- Hurry up.
- Alright, I'll be right there.
I'd like to hear that march again.
What lucky timing.
Should I wear my raincoat?
I will take both.
At your service, colonel.
- They're suspecting us.
- So what?
From suspecting to accusing
there's only one step.
Is there any proof?
Can't you see that all the elements
of a crime are there?
The police, the unexpected question,
the anguish and a corpse.
A corpse?
The play is completed.
Also the atmosphere.
A small hotel, supporting characters:
a caretaker and a waitress.
What do you mean?
Don't you realize this is as
absurd as in my novels?
But now I'm not the author,
I am the assassin.
You're not an assassin.
It doesn't matter that my
hands aren't really bloody.
Crimes aren't only committed
with the hands.
You and I had the will to kill.
Don't you realize?
We've jumped over that fence,
we're on the other side.
What fence are you talking about?
The one that divides life from death.
Haven't you seen me lying
and attacking the police?
I wasn't feigning. I swear,
I felt hate.
Do you know why, Ivón?
Nobody can stop this now.
We've got the red fishes inside.
- They're here.
- Shut up.
The red fishes, going 'round
and 'round the fish tank.
Haven't you ever seen them
going 'round?
When bloody thoughts arise
they start going 'round...
...and 'round until you go crazy.
Until they make you kill.
- Mr. Commissioner.
- What's the matter?
They've gone away!
He's gone first. Both of them
have gone away running.
- In which direction?
- To the pier.
- Are they crazy?
- Let them...
I think it would be better
to call the Guardia Civil.
There's no time for that. I'm afraid that
man could be a victim of his own lie.
Do you think he's gonna
commit suicide?
No, no, no!
Hugo, Hugo!
Leave me alone. Get away!
I've gotta do it,
don't you understand?
- I can't live this way. I killed him.
- It's not real, everything is a lie!
I love you, I love you
with all my heart.
If you jump, I'll jump too.
I don't wanna live without you.
I need you.
Confess everything. I'll always
be by your side. Always.
Forget that lie and tell them
the truth like I'm telling you to.
I want you by my side, Hugo.
Tell them the truth.